susquehanna.net 2008-06-28

# Susquehanna > About Us > Privacy

Susquehanna Bancshares, Inc., is a family of member companies and related financial businesses that includes:  **Susquehanna Bank,**  Hagerstown, MD;  **Susquehanna Bank PA** , Lititz, PA; and **Susquehanna Bank DV** , Bryn Mawr, PA. This notice relates to these companies. 

We believe that protecting the privacy and confidentiality of your personal information is very important. We value your business and the trust you have placed in us. 

In order to provide you with the level of service you deserve, we collect, maintain, and use information about you. To help you better understand how your information is protected, we are providing you with the following privacy statement describing our policies and practices. This statement is provided to you on behalf of all the financial institutions listed above. 

Should you no longer be our customer, or if your accounts with us become inactive, we will continue to follow the policies and practices described in this notice.

  * Information We Collect
  * Information We Share
  * Who Receives Information and Why
  * Service Providers/Joint Marketing Partners
  * Information Sharing Within Our Corporate Family
  * Former Customers
  * How We Protect Your Information
  * Changes
  * Opt-Out Selection Form
  * Internet Privacy Notice

**Information We Collect**  
We collect, maintain, and use non-public personal information about our customers. Non-public personal information is taken from sources such as: 

  * applications or other forms; 
  * your transaction records on file with us, our affiliates, or others; and 
  * consumer reporting agencies

**Information We Share**   
We may share all of the information we collect about you with the businesses within our corporate family. 

  1. Currently, we share only the following types of information (which we refer to in this notice as "Transactional Information"): 
    * transaction data on file with us and businesses within our corporate family, including your name, address, account balance, payment history, parties to transactions, and debit card usage.
  2. We reserve the right to share the following types of information (which we refer to in this notice as "Credit Report Information") within our corporate family: 
    * information we receive from you on applications or other forms, such as your social security number, your income, and your assets and liabilities; 
    * information we receive from a consumer reporting agency, such as your credit score and your credit history; 
    * information we obtain from another person regarding your employment, credit, or other relationship with you, such as your employment history; and 
    * aggregated demographic data about you, such as likely lifestyle information and likely income and asset characteristics.

**Who Receives Information and Why**   
There are certain situations where we may share non-public personal information about you with businesses outside of our corporate family as permitted by law. We will not, however, share any information with companies outside of the financial services industry for purposes of marketing that company's products and services. We may share information within our corporate family. The following is a description of the types of businesses within our corporate family with which we may share information: 

  * financial service providers such as banks, a registered investment advisor, a mortgage company, a securities broker-dealer, a trust company, insurance agencies, and an automobile leasing company.

**Service Providers/Joint Marketing Partners**   
In order to provide you with valuable financial products or services, we may share with businesses outside of our corporate family both Transactional Information and Credit Report Information. These businesses will be performing marketing and other services on our behalf. We also may share this information with other financial institutions with which we have joint marketing agreements. 

**Information Sharing Within Our Corporate Family**   
We may share with the businesses within our corporate family Transactional Information for any reason. However, you can tell us not to share your Credit Report Information, within our corporate family, by simply following the instructions on the attached Opt-Out Selection Form.

**Please Note the Following:**

  * If you send us a completed Opt-Out Selection Form, we may still share, within our corporate family, Transactional Information for any reason. 
  * We are required to provide you with a copy of our Customer Privacy Notice each year. If you have previously sent us a written notice choosing an opt-out right, you DO NOT need to do so again. Your previous notice to us will continue to be honored. 
  * If your account ownership rights or obligations involve two or more people, then we will treat the receipt of an Opt-Out Selection Form from any one owner as the opt-out of all owners. 

**Former Customers**   
All of the practices described in this notice apply to former customers as well.

**How We Protect Your Information**   
We have strict policies and procedures to safeguard your privacy. Some of these measures involve technology that is required to maintain data security. Some are more traditional and include such things as training employees about the importance of confidentiality and customer privacy and of limiting access to certain information on a need-to-know business basis. We review and update our practices as needed to maintain security.

**Changes**   
We may amend this privacy notice at any time, and we will inform you of changes as required by law. 

**Opt-Out Selection Form**   
You may instruct us not to share your Credit Report Information within our corporate family for marketing purposes. If you make this choice, then you must complete our opt-out form, print it and send it in a stamped envlope to:

Susquehanna Bancshares, Inc.  
Account Services, CIF Department  
P.O. Box 1000  
26 North Cedar Street  
Lititz, PA 17543

_If you already have notified us about your privacy choice, then you do not need to do so again. Your previous notice to us will continued to be honored._

Download [Opt-Out Selection Form](http://www.susquehanna.net/misc/optOut.pdf)  (Fill it out online, then print.)   
If Adobe Reader is not installed on your PC, a free download is available through Adobe's Web site.

**Privacy Notice**   
Susquehanna respects the privacy of its online banking customers and is committed to protecting their information on our Web site. Whether you are a current customer or just visiting online, we safeguard the information you provide to us. We only collect non-identifying information about our visitors such as date and time our site was accessed, what pages were visited, what servers were used, and the city, state and country of the visitor as identified by the server address. Susquehanna collects this information to create summary statistics and determine the level of interest in our information made available on our Web site that helps us to establish products and services to best meet our customers' needs. 

Visitors may elect to submit personal information via email, by submitting an application, or by requesting information. This information may be used internally by Susquehanna, as appropriate, to handle the sender's request. It is not disseminated or sold to other organizations. 

We reserve the right to introduce new services or practices that may require a change to the provisions of this notice. We are committed to updating our Internet Privacy Notice promptly to keep you informed on how we use information you give us.
